

# Alysson Cirilo

Software Engineer



Brazil



https://www.github.com/alyssoncs



alysson.cirilo@gmail.com

## About me-

I've always wanted to learn how things work under the hood, and since I got my first computer it became clear to me what I was going to do for the rest of my days. I strongly believe that creating technology is one of the most human activities there is.

Portuguese

English

C programming Language

Java

Kotlin

Linux

Android Development

Arduino

Git

Docker

MongoDB

(\*)[The skill scale is from 0 (Fundamental Awareness) to 6 (Expert).]

### interests

I've became very interested in subjects like algorithms, operating systems, system development, IoT and much more.

System development, Android development and Software Architecture are some of the subjects that I'm currently interested in and studying.

#### education

2013-2019 B.Sc. in Computer Science

UFMA

Discovery and Disconnection of Smart Objects in Opportunistic IoMT Environments

### experience

2020-Now Mid-level Developer Secretaria de Estado de Administração Penitenciária do

Maranhão (SEAP)

 Development of the mobile Android version using Kotlin of the system that allows searching information about the state's prisoners and fugitives.

2019–2020 Junior Developer

Secretaria de Estado de Administração Penitenciária do

Maranhão (SEAP)

- Became in charge of the design, build and deployment of a flexible service and API for storing log information of other systems using MongoDB;
- Implementation of a mobile application following the Clean Architecture principles, using native Android with Kotlin and Firebase Cloud Messaging, this app allowed visitors to schedule virtual visits to their imprisoned family members, important resource during the Covid-19 pandemic;
- Also part of a group responsible for the maintenance and implementation of new features of the system that manages all state's prison information.

2019-2019 Intern

Laboratory of Intelligent Distributed Systems

Development of a bluetooth beacon-based indoor location system, con-

sisting of: Development of the subsystem responsible to manage the relationships

- between users, bluetooth beacons and physical spaces using the Spring Boot framework and PostgreSQL;
- Development of an Android application able to detect bluetooth beacons in the environment and registering this encounter in a Web service using Retrofit.

2017–2019 Undergraduate Research Fellow

Laboratory of Intelligent Distributed Systems

• Implementation of new functionalities in an existing IoT middleware using Java on the Android platform, including a notification mechanism for discovery, connection and disconnection of smart objects;

- Development of embedded software using the C programming language on Arduino boards, including the use of Bluetooth Low Energy technology;
- Integration between the embedded and mobile software using Bluetooth Low Energy and MQTT technologies.

#### other information

Pursuing a computer science degree was the next logical step to make. I became passionate about many fields.

Eventually I came to the conclusion that mastering the basis, the fundamentals, is the way to go to be a competent professional, so I usually follow a bottom-up approach when studying any subjects.